<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Kevin Wilde]]></title><description><![CDATA[Personal website for Kevin Wilde]]></description><link>https://kevinwil.de/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 04:58:32 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[Incremental Migration]]></title><description><![CDATA[TypeScript has exploded in popularity over the past couple years. If you asked a typical developer why they think this has happened, they…]]></description><link>https://kevinwil.de//incremental-migration/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kevinwil.de//incremental-migration/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;TypeScript has exploded in popularity over the past couple years. If you asked a typical developer why they think this has happened, they might say something about the value of static type-checking. It helps prevent bugs, it’s easier to understand code when you precisely know the shape of objects, it enables a better developer experience, it allows for greater confidence when refactoring, etc. These are all great benefits of using TypeScript, but in my opinion these benefits alone would not have been sufficient for TypeScript to become popular.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A key feature of TypeScript is that it is extremely easy to use it incrementally migrate an existing JavaScript codebase to TypeScript. An incremental migration path is one of the most essential conditions for the successful adoption of a programming language, framework, library, tool, etc. React and GraphQL are two other examples of projects that I don’t think would have gotten as popular as they are today if they hadn’t provided such a good migration path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Course Hero, we began using TypeScript a few years ago, slowly transitioning our frontend JavaScript code to TypeScript. Because we were transitioning existing JavaScript code, we set up our &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;tsconfig.json&lt;/code&gt; to be “lenient”. &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;noImplicitAny&lt;/code&gt; were both set to false. In an ideal world, or if you are starting a new TypeScript project from scratch, it is very useful to have these settings turned on. When they are off, TypeScript will allow the following code:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;typescript&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-typescript&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-typescript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;function&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;strLen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token parameter&quot;&gt;s&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;string&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token builtin&quot;&gt;number&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; s&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;length
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;strLen&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;null&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this will result in an error at runtime. The point of using TypeScript is to catch type errors at build time! With &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks&lt;/code&gt; turned on, the TypeScript compiler will in fact catch this error and fail to compile your code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned, though, we were migrating a significant amount of JavaScript code to TypeScript. We wanted to be able to start using TypeScript immediately without having to fix all of the places that would fail these stricter checks. Using a “lenient” &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;tsconfig.json&lt;/code&gt; allowed us to start reaping some of the benefits of TypeScript immediately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After all of our non-legacy frontend code had been migrated to TypeScript, we decided that it should be a goal to turn on &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;noImplicitAny&lt;/code&gt;. However, it wasn’t practical to try to change all the places that needed to be fixed at once. In a codebase as large as ours, there were thousands of errors when trying to compile with these stricter settings. We needed an incremental migration path!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our build process is set up in such a way that we can compile apps separately when doing local development, and then when we push to production, our CI will only compile the apps that have changed even though they are in a monolithic codebase. Because we have this per-app build process, we just modified it slightly to allow each app to configure its own settings for &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;noImplicitAny&lt;/code&gt;. This way those settings could be turned on one app at a time. It would be much easier to get one app to comply with these stricter checks than to try to get all of our apps to comply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each app has a small build config file (to configure a bundle name, entry point, and output path). This file is where we could configure &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;noImplicitAny&lt;/code&gt; for just that app. To encourage apps to turn on these settings, an engineer added the following lines to all of our app config files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;text&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks: false, // TODO change to true
noImplicityAny: false, // TODO change to true&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that, we had an incremental migration path in place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast forward a year, and I started thinking about &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;noImplicitAny&lt;/code&gt; again. I was working on an app that a different team had written, so I wasn’t very familiar with it, and it was frustrating to never be certain if an object really matched the type it had been annotated with or if it was &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;null&lt;/code&gt;. I decided to check if we made any progress on moving towards &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;noImplicitAny&lt;/code&gt;. Looking at our app config files, I found that a grand total of 0 of those &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;TODO change to true&lt;/code&gt;s had been done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our incremental migration path wasn’t working.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why didn’t this path work? One obvious reason stood out to me, and it has to do with IDEs. When writing TypeScript code, IDEs use &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;tsconfig.json&lt;/code&gt; to determine what they should underline as an error. Since our &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;tsconfig.json&lt;/code&gt; still had &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;noImplicitAny&lt;/code&gt; set to false, people didn’t even realize when they were writing code that would fail these checks. Their IDE didn’t report any errors and the build task succeeded, so how could they know? This meant that rather than moving closer towards enabling &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;noImplicitAny&lt;/code&gt;, we were actively adding code that was not compliant with &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;noImplicitAny&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I thought about this, I began working on a different incremental migration strategy. First, we would set &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;noImplicitAny&lt;/code&gt; to true in &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;tsconfig.json&lt;/code&gt;. This would cause developers to become aware of the places that didn’t comply with these checks and hopefully allow them to comply with these checks perfectly when writing new code. During the build process, we would override these two settings with whatever value was configured for them in the app config file. This would allow all of our apps to still compile, while surfacing the errors to developers in their IDEs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shortly after I put this strategy in place, a friend sent me this great &lt;a href=&quot;https://code.visualstudio.com/blogs/2019/05/23/strict-null&quot;&gt;blog post from the VS Code team&lt;/a&gt; about how they migrated to strict null checks. The basic approach is that they had a list of files that were already compliant with strict null checks. During the build process, they make sure that there’s no regressions in any of these files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized that we could adopt this same strategy at Course Hero. The VS Code team wrote a couple scripts to automatically generate the list of files that are already compliant with strict null checks, and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mjbvz/vscode-strict-null-check-migration-tools&quot;&gt;shared them on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;. I forked these scripts and adapted them to the Course Hero codebase. I was able to generate a list of our own files that were already compliant with strict null checks and added a step to the build process to run the TypeScript compiler against this list of files. Now, we are able to prevent regressions against strict null checks by failing the build when a regression happens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By surfacing errors in the IDE and preventing regressions during the build process, we are having much more success at moving towards enabling &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;strictNullChecks&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;noImplicitAny&lt;/code&gt;. We still aren’t there yet, but we’re making progress!&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[ClassNamed Components]]></title><description><![CDATA[At Course Hero, we aren’t yet using a CSS-in-JS library. Instead, we have a css framework that is largely based on Bootstrap 4. While CSS-in…]]></description><link>https://kevinwil.de//classnamed-components/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kevinwil.de//classnamed-components/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;At Course Hero, we aren’t yet using a CSS-in-JS library. Instead, we have a css framework that is largely based on Bootstrap 4. While CSS-in-JS libraries provide &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.styled-components.com/docs/basics#motivation&quot;&gt;many benefits&lt;/a&gt; over external stylesheets, and we may eventually use CSS-in-JS, for now our css framework is serving us well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One benefit our css framework gives us is more consistent styling, in a way that might be more difficult to enforce if we used CSS-in-JS. For example, when we need some margin around an element, the intent is that the developer should only ever use one of the margin classes from our css framework, rather than writing an arbitrary margin rule. This has greatly improved the design consistency on our pages. Previously, it was not uncommon to see some element that has a margin of 47px or some other seemingly random number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although there are clear differences between using our css framework and using CSS-in-JS, I actually find the authoring experience quite similar. Since our css framework has utility classes for all the common css rules, using those classes inside a component has a similar feel to writing your styles directly in the component as you might do with CSS-in-JS. For example, with &lt;a href=&quot;https://emotion.sh/docs/introduction&quot;&gt;Emotion&lt;/a&gt; you might write&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;css&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token script language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token script-punctuation punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    margin&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;1.5rem&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    padding&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;1rem&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
    border&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;1px solid #dee2e6&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token plain-text&quot;&gt;
  blah blah blah
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;and with Bootstrap 4, you would write&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;className&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token attr-value&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;m-4 p-3 border&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token plain-text&quot;&gt;
  blah blah blah
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you get the hang of all the utility classes, the development experience starts to feel pretty nice. You can adjust the styling of your component without having to switch to another file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As your design gets a little more complex, though, your className becomes a little longer. Pretty soon you’re writing lines like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;className&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token attr-value&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;d-none d-md-block p-0 rounded border border-warning position-fixed mb-3&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token plain-text&quot;&gt;
  blah blah blah
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then maybe you come back to that component a couple weeks later and someone else has added to it. The render method has gotten long. Once you have some nested elements, all with long classNames, your react component starts looking pretty sloppy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, breaking down the component into smaller pieces helps significantly, but maybe we can also take some inspiration from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.styled-components.com/&quot;&gt;styled-components&lt;/a&gt;. With styled-components, you write something like this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; Wrapper &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; styled&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;div&lt;span class=&quot;token template-string&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;`
  padding: 0;
  border-radius: 0.25rem;
  border: 1px solid yellow;
  position: fixed;
  margin-bottom: 1rem;
`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;// Then use it in your render method like&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Wrapper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token plain-text&quot;&gt;
  blah blah blah
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Wrapper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This keeps your render method very clean, and the styles are still colocated with the component. Can we do something similar when we’re using a css framework? Of course!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function-variable function&quot;&gt;Wrapper&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token parameter&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; children &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;className&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token attr-value&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;d-none d-md-block p-0 rounded border border-warning position-fixed mb-3&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token plain-text&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;children&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token plain-text&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;token comment&quot;&gt;// Then use it in your render method like&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Wrapper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token plain-text&quot;&gt;
  blah blah blah
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Wrapper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing this can greatly improve the readability of your render method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the API for styled-components is a little nicer because you don’t have to manually say that you want to render &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;props.children&lt;/code&gt; every time you make a styled component. So let’s create a function that allows us to write&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; Wrapper &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;classNamedComponent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;div&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&quot;d-none d-md-block p-0 rounded border border-warning position-fixed mb-3&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementing &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;classNamedComponent&lt;/code&gt; is fairly straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function-variable function&quot;&gt;classNamedComponent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token parameter&quot;&gt;Element&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; className&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token parameter&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; children &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Element&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;className&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token script language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token script-punctuation punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;className&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;children&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Element&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But now, we have lost the ability to change the className based on props. In our previous, more verbose implementation, it was easy. For example, we can change the border color based on an error prop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function-variable function&quot;&gt;Wrapper&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token parameter&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; children&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; error &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;div&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;className&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token script language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token script-punctuation punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token template-string&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;`d-none d-md-block p-0 rounded border &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token interpolation&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token interpolation-punctuation punctuation&quot;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;
      error &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;border-warning&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;border-succes&apos;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token interpolation-punctuation punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt; position-fixed mb-3`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token plain-text&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;children&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token plain-text&quot;&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;div&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But how would we do this with our &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;classNamedComponent&lt;/code&gt; version? Again, we can take inspiration from styled-components. The library uses tagged template literals to enable you to pass functions to your styled component, and that’s what we’ll need to do to. Max Stoiber, the creator of styled-components, wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://mxstbr.blog/2016/11/styled-components-magic-explained/&quot;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt; explaining how it works in depth. I also found &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/styled-components/how-styled-components-works-618a69970421&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; that gives a simplified implementation of styled-components. Using that article as a starting point, I modified the &lt;code class=&quot;language-text&quot;&gt;classNamedComponent&lt;/code&gt; function so that it can be used like&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; Wrapper &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;classNamedComponent&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;div&apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token template-string&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;`
  d-none
  d-md-block
  p-0
  rounded
  border
  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token interpolation&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token interpolation-punctuation punctuation&quot;&gt;${&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt; error &lt;span class=&quot;token interpolation-punctuation punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;) =&gt; error ? &apos;border-warning&apos; : &apos;border-success&apos;}
  position-fixed
  mb-3
`&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the implementation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;gatsby-highlight&quot; data-language=&quot;jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-jsx&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function-variable function&quot;&gt;classNamedComponent&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token parameter&quot;&gt;Element&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token parameter&quot;&gt;strs&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;exprs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token parameter&quot;&gt;props&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; result &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;props&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;className&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; strs&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; index &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; index &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; exprs&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;length&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; index&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; expr &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; exprs&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;index&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;const&lt;/span&gt; value &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;typeof&lt;/span&gt; expr &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;===&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos;function&apos;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;?&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;expr&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;props&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt; expr
    result&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;push&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;value&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; strs&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;index&lt;span class=&quot;token operator&quot;&gt;+&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token number&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

  &lt;span class=&quot;token keyword&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token tag&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token class-name&quot;&gt;Element&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;token spread&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;...&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token attr-value&quot;&gt;props&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;token attr-name&quot;&gt;className&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token script language-javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token script-punctuation punctuation&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
        result
          &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;filter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;Boolean&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;join&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos; &apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;replace&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token regex&quot;&gt;/\s+/g&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;token string&quot;&gt;&apos; &apos;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
          &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token function&quot;&gt;trim&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
      &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;/&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;token punctuation&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that for simplicity, I’m passing all the props through to the element. In reality, you’d want to use &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.com/package/@emotion/is-prop-valid&quot;&gt;@emotion/is-prop-valid&lt;/a&gt; (or something similar) the way that &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/styled-components/styled-components/blob/7002c1e4a52a84be42f607ca7cc3bdbea22f2a24/packages/styled-components/src/models/StyledComponent.js#L144&quot;&gt;styled-components does&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this was a fun exercise in thinking about developer experience when writing and styling react components, and it also gave me the chance to get a deeper understanding of how the styled-components library works.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>